本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 粟 许块块 狐狸锁骨 我很好 小白
校对： 许块块   后期： 泡面君
我会大声叫的 别过来
And I'm not keeping quiet. No.
别过来 走开!
No, keep away!
别过来! 走开!
Get back! No, get away!
放开我!
Let go!
救命!
Help!
费雪小姐探案集 第二季第十一集
死亡直播间
可以接收到多少个电台?
How many stations can it pick up?
恐怕只有3Jh 因为有限制执照
Only 3JH, I'm afraid. That's how a restricted licence works
那太好了
That's perfect.
那请问这3Jh有什么特别的吗?
May I ask what's so particular about this 3JH?
里面有关于庞静赫尔的
It has The Polkinghorns.
一个曾经在我学校读书的女孩帮忙制作的
A girl who went to my school helps to make it.
现在重新回到了我们的每日剧集
Now it's time to revisit our daily serial,
与庞静赫尔在家中
At Home With The Polkinghorns.
新的一天
A New Day.
我好像听到了的士的声音
That sounds like the taxi now.
玛丽斯
Maurice...
肯定是我们的格温妮亚回来了
..it must be our Guinevere,
赶上了她二十一岁的生日
home in time for her 21st birthday.
- 谁是格温妮亚? - 他们的女儿
- Who's Guinevere? - Their daughter.
看看外面 玛丽斯 是我们的格温妮亚
Look outside, Maurice - our Guinevere.
- 她人呢? - 嘘
- Where is she? - Ssh!
我...
I...
在她做了那些事后 我不想再见到她
..don't want to see her after what she did.
她做了什么?
What did she do?
和一个意大利歌剧歌手私奔了
Ran off with an Italian opera singer.
果真如此
We've all done that.
但我们正在直播
But we are on air.
继续啊!
(Come on!)
女佣怎么耽搁这么久?
Whatever is keeping that maid?
- 她死了 - 谁死了?
- She's dead. - Who's dead?
路易莎 到外面来 把那东西关掉!
Louisa, outside. Just turn the blasted thing off!
路易莎・金乐顿是我那朋友
L... Louisa Singleton is the girl I know.
电台称是报社引起的战争 将在阿格斯上演
Radios claim newspaper war. Out now in the Argus.
费雪小姐 你怎么知道的?
Ah, Miss Fisher. How did you know?
我们刚才在听无线电台
We were listening to the wireless.
路易莎这一生原有很多美好的打算
Louisa was going to do so many wonderful things.
我是侦探费雪小姐
Miss Fisher, detective,
这是我的助理威廉姆斯小姐
and my assistant, Miss Williams.
我是吉米・克里斯维奇 3Jh电台的经理
Jimmy Creswick, station manager, 3JH,
这是我的妻子海斯尔
and my wife, Hazel.
这是路易莎?
And this is Louisa?
是的 我们的得力助手
Yes, our Girl Friday,
路易莎・金乐顿小姐
Miss Louisa Singleton.
真让人悲伤
How awful.
- 他们说会找上我们的 - 谁?
- They said they'd get us. - Who did?
海斯尔 亲爱的 到里面休息冷静一下
Hazel, love, come inside and calm down.
看起来她是被勒死的
Looks like she was strangled.
真可惜 她还那么年轻
Such a shame, one so young.
- 真可怕 - 如果她昨天是穿着这身衣服
- Terrible. - Time of death, 6:40pm,
并且在当时手表正常工作的话
if we assume she was wearing these clothes yesterday
她的死亡时间是傍晚六点四十分
and her watch was in good working order.
谢谢 剩下的由我来处理 请往后退 谢谢
Thank you. I'll take it from here. Step back, please. Thank you.
请往后退
Step right back, please.
罗宾森警探呢?
Where's Inspector Robinson?
他... 他正在调查另一个案件
He's... He's on another job.
那我们可以帮你 休斯
We'd be happy to assist you, Hugh.
金乐顿小姐以前在学校里是多蒂的朋友
Miss Singleton was a school friend of Dot's.
如果我不帮忙 她不会原谅我的
She'd never forgive me if I didn't help.
小姐
Miss?
警探正在乔装卧底
The other job the Inspector's on...
调查另一个机密的案子
..he's uncover and it's confidential.
真有趣 走吧 多蒂
Sounds intriguing. Come on, Dot.
是的 就是她昨天所穿的衣服
Yes, exactly the same outfit that she was in yesterday.
我们只是以为她早上迟到了
We just thought she was late this morning.
尽管路易莎从来不会迟到 今天是第一次
Even though Louisa was never late. Today of all days.
在庞静赫尔家饰演格温妮亚对她而言很重要
Playing Guinevere in The Polkinghorns was her big step up.
有人想要蓄意伤害金乐顿小姐吗
Is there anyone who might have wanted to harm Miss Singleton?
没有 路易莎把她的精力都放在工作上
No. Louisa put all her efforts into her work.
好姑娘 书本整理好 剧本也都是她打的
Top girl. She kept the books neat, typed up all our scripts.
她接受了3Jh的工作后
She broke it off with her fiance in Perth
在珀斯和未婚夫分手了
when she was offered the job at 3JH.
这里有路易莎的衣服吗?
Are any of these coats Louisa's?
那披风就是她的
Yes, the cloak.
我可以帮你做记录
I can scribe, if you like.
没有任何的抱怨或者威胁吗?
So no grudges, threats?
没有专门针对她的
Not against her in particular.
几天前有几通电话
There were telephone calls a few days ago.
海斯尔接了一通 路易莎接了另一通
Hazel took one, Louisa the other.
对方是一个男人
It was a man.
他警告我们 把电台关掉 不然他就亲自动手
He warned us to shut down the station or he'd do it himself.
因此我们知道会有麻烦
We've been expecting trouble.
别的电台都有受到攻击
There have been attacks on other radio stations.
我们从最高点跌倒了低谷
From our brightest night to our darkest day.
昨晚海斯尔在澳大利亚电台表演颁奖礼上
Hazel was crowned Best Female Talent last night
被誉为最有天赋的女性
at the Australian Recorded Performance Awards.
哦 不!
Oh, no!
奥斯沃德
Oh, Oswald.
没事 海斯尔 只是一条金鱼
Come now, Hazel. It's only a goldfish.
它可能只是寿命已尽了
It was probably his time.
对不起 我平常不这样的
Sorry. I'm not normally like this.
早安 现在是十点新闻
Good morning. This is the Ten O'clock News.
从七月份开始
From July,
有轨电车会从东边城郊部分开通
electric trams will run from the eastern suburbs.
这声音!
That voice!
这不但能减缓市中心的交通问题
This is predicted not only to alleviate traffic in the centre
更能为城市带来更多的消费者
but bring new shoppers to the city,
让他们享受商店豪华的阵容
where they can enjoy a splendid array
以及餐厅各类的美味
of stores and restaurants that cater to all tastes.
阿奇伯・琼斯先生 他声音很悦耳
Mr Archibald Jones, he of the dulcet tones.
你们是怎么找到他的?
Wherever did you find him?
不是我们找的
We didn't.
3Jh董事会在上周决定开播一小时新闻节目
The board of 3JH decided last week to offer an hourly news service.
原本我们打算培训克莱瑞斯来担任主持
We wanted to train Clarence for the role
可经理请了琼斯先生
but management hired Mr Jones.
你去坐下来休息一下好吗 亲爱的?
Why don't you go and have a sit-down, love?
你受到惊吓了
You've had a shock.
是啊 宝贝 我确实感到有些累
You're right, darling. I do feel slightly shattered.
我刚认识她的时候
She couldn't get out more than two words
她站在麦克风前都说不出话
in front of a microphone when I first met her.
或许有个私人侦探能让她安心些
Perhaps having a private detective around would reassure her,
侦探会谨慎点
a discreet presence.
要是我说 最需要被要看紧的是这个家伙
If you ask me, the one to look out for is that bloke.
我一点也不相信他
I wouldn't trust him as far as I could spit.
下个小时 将会给大家带来
There will be more news in the next hour,
更多的新闻 不要走开
so please stay tuned.
稍后 将会由克莱瑞斯・鲍尔
Shortly, Clarence Ball will be with you
带来每日体育新闻
for the daily sporting news.
但请先欣赏一段音乐
But first, a musical interlude.
在你解释前 阿奇伯...
Before you say anything, Archibald...
谢天谢地你在这里 我需要你接手这件案子
Thank goodness you're here. I need you to move in on this case.
柯林斯一个人处理不了
Collins can't handle this alone.
是杰克・罗宾森在说话吗?
Is this Jack Robinson speaking,
还是你仍在隐姓埋名?
or are you still incognito?
你是想让我帮助休斯
You want me to ride shotgun over Hugh
希望你换种说法
I wish you wouldn't put it quite like that.
- 那你可以友好地问我 - 想让我求你?
- You could ask nicely. - Want me to beg?
就此一次而已
This may never happen again.
求你了
Please.
我只能呆在这留意观察
I'm stuck here, keeping an eye on things.
那你太不细心了
Not a very keen eye.
有人在傍晚六点四十分被杀了
Someone was killed at 6:40pm, to be precise.
昨晚我向市政厅作报告
I was reporting to Commissioner Hall last night.
在过去的六个月里
Four radio stations from Melbourne and Sydney
从墨尔本到悉尼 有四家电台关门了
have been shut down in the last six months.
他们被抢劫 被肆意破坏 或者被纵火
They've been robbed, vandalised or set alight.
我们都知道 一旦电台倒闭了 谁的收益最大
Well, we both know who has the most to lose, with radio taking off.
报社 如果能在无限电台听到新闻
Newspapers. Why buy a newspaper
就没有必要再买报纸了
if you've already heard the headlines on the wireless?
你现在怀疑有内奸?
But you suspect an inside job?
克莱瑞斯・鲍尔 就是那家伙
Clarence Ball - foley man,
弹钢琴的 也是体育播报员
piano player, sports presenter.
一系列电话骚扰后 他离开了
Left radio station 3XL one week before it burned to the ground
3Xl电台没多久 电台就被烧成了灰
after a series of menacing phone calls.
这么巧的时间
Suspiciously good timing.
先来看看狂欢夜少女
Let's have a look at the Corroborree Maiden first.
在第七场 我选择了复活节再会 二号
In the seventh, my pick is Paschal Vaya, number two.
在第八场 我们关注五号...
In the eighth, we're looking at number five...
克莱瑞斯・鲍尔在直播 我听了不少
Clarence Ball's On The Track. I've heard a lot about this.
他的建议有什么特别的?
What's so remarkable about these tips?
有些并不准
Not very good odds, some of them.
我也这么认为 这只是他的喜好而已
I'm with you. These are just all the favourites.
酒吧老板跟着这家伙赚了一大笔钱
The barman at the pub is making a packet out of this bloke.
就是跟着他下的注
Col swears by him.
请在下午的老时间调到名人堂
Tune in this afternoon at the usual time for Hall Of Fame -
将是你猜中当代雌马的机会
your chance to guess our Mare of the Moment.
我们肯定漏掉了什么
Nah. We're missing something with this joker.
昨天最后一场比赛在六点五十五分无线播出
The results of the last race came in on the wire at 6:55,
接着电台在七点关门
then the station closed at seven.
因此你是最后一个离开办公室的?
You were the last to leave the office?
没错
That's right.
吉米和海斯尔在五点三十分离开 去了颁奖礼
Jimmy and Hazel left at 5:30 to go to a... fancy awards do.
看起来克里斯维奇夫人让3Jh成功不少啊
Looks like Mrs Creswick has really made 3JH a success story.
墨尔本电台的最佳女主播奖
Best Female Talent on Melbourne Radio
要知道多少人听我的体育新闻下注
You'd be surprised how many punters tune
你会大吃一惊
in to my sporting news,
跟我现场直播下注的更多
even more to my live race calls.
你应该刚来这电台没多久 是吗?
But... you haven't been at the station for long, have you?
- 之前你在哪高就? - 3Xl电台
- Where were you previously? - Radio 3XL.
在那儿我也有很多听众
I had quite a following there too.
那电台倒闭了 是吗?
That station closed down, didn't it?
我记得是发生了场火灾
A fire, I believe.
那时
Before my time.
我们产生了争执
Difference of opinion.
回到金乐顿小姐的身上
Back to Miss Singleton,
昨晚她是几点离开办公室的?
what time did she leave the office last night?
她在我上班前给我沏了杯茶
She made me a cuppa before my shift.
接着在晚班七点结束以前
Then there was no sign of her
我都没有再见到她
when the evening session finished at seven.
路易莎负责什么工作?
What was Louisa working on?
简单的诗歌 给节目出主意 写故事
Jingles, ideas for shows, stories.
我告诉她这完全是在浪费时间
I told her it was a complete waste of time.
海斯尔确保她写的每个字都会播出
Hazel made damn sure she wrote every word that went to air.
她没想到路易莎对此有觊觎?
She didn't think Louisa was up to the task?
那你得问海斯尔了
You'd have to ask Hazel that.
就你所知 他们吵过架吗?
Did they ever disagree, to your knowledge?
海斯尔最近很麻烦
Hazel's been tricky lately.
路易莎也不是她骂过的第一个了
Louisa wouldn't be the only one she's crossed swords with.
你最好合作 阿奇
You'd better cooperate, Archie.
吉米已经认为是你下手的了
Jimmy already thinks you did it.
- 什么? - 你确实举止怪异
- What? - You are behaving very suspiciously.
克莱瑞斯有机会谋杀路易莎啊
Clarence had the opportunity to murder Louisa.
他在音乐播放期间很容易溜出播音间啊
He could easily slip out of the studio in a musical interlude.
海斯尔和路易莎关系不好 创新力竞争
Hazel and Louisa didn't get on. Creative competition.
你们又看到播音顺序吗?
Have you seen a running order anywhere?
我们失去了路易莎一团乱
We're in such a mess without Louisa.
在这
Here it is.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
也许多蒂能帮上忙
Perhaps Dot could be of some help.
那就太棒了
That would be wonderful.
我带你看看要做什么
I'll show you what needs to be done.
警察有嫌疑犯了吗?
So, do the police have any ideas?
任何人都有可能 你也知道谁成天在那晃
Could be anyone. You know the type who hang around here.
谁啊?
Like who?
卖报的小伙就算一个
That bloke from the newspaper stand for one.
路易莎抱怨他总是随心所欲晃进来
Louisa complained about him waltzing in here whenever he felt like it.
我真希望当时多留意他 采取些行动
I only wish I'd taken more notice and done something about him.
给你 谢谢 科博
There you go. Thanks, cobber.
阿格斯 谢谢
Argus, thanks.
你对路易莎很熟咯?
So, you knew Louisa pretty well?
我希望多了解她
I'd hoped to know her even better.
我几次邀请她去跳舞
I asked her to go dancing a couple of times.
- 她拒绝了? - 拒了两次而已
- She turned you down? - Only twice.
我还有机会的
I was still in with a chance.
我从她想激怒我的举止中悟到的
I could tell by the way she liked to tick me off.
我昨晚也见她了 她从我这买了小面包
I saw her last night too. She bought a bun from me.
说她要回去工作了
Said she was going back to work.
也许你该告诉警察
Maybe you should tell the cops.
我才不要招惹上警察
I'm not getting mixed up with the cops,
那也不会路易莎死而复生
and it won't bring Louisa back.
来买报纸哟! 报纸!
Get your papers here! Paper!
你确定我们没遗漏什么 休斯?
Are you sure there's nothing we've missed, Hugh?
她想嫁给那个珀斯的小伙
She wanted to marry that bloke in Perth,
但是却醉心于广播事业
but she had her heart set on radio.
是的 路易莎 和我一样十五岁离开学校
Yes, Louisa, she left school at 15, like me,
可她一直很聪明
but she was always smart.
你也很聪明啊 协助女侦探工作
Well, you must be smart too, assisting a lady detective.
好吧 来测测你
Rightio, let's test you.
猜这只鸟
Guess this bird.
- 我放弃 - 这是黑天鹅
- I give up. - That is the black swan,
西澳大利亚的官方标志鸟
the official bird of Western Australia.
我让你笑了 不是吗?
But I made you smile, didn't I?
你同僚去世还真对你影响颇深啊
Deeply affected by your colleague's passing, are you?
你什么毛病 警员? 我跟你交代完了
What's your problem, Constable? I've told you everything I know.
你昨晚为何没听见小巷里有干扰?
Why didn't you hear any disturbance in the alley last night?
外面可能有枪战
There could have been heavy mortar fire outside
我都听不到的
and I wouldn't have heard a thing.
播音室是隔音的
That studio is completely soundproof.
救人啊 警员 快来救人!
Help! Constable, help, quickly!
噢 吉米!
Oh, Jimmy!
往后站 海斯尔 别动!
Stay back, Hazel. Don't touch it!
- 怎么回事? - 麦克风 电到我了
- What happened? - The microphone. I got a shock.
- 别靠近 - 关掉电源
- Stand back, please. - Turn off the power.
大厅里有保险丝
There's a fuse box in the hall.
危机解除
All clear.
有急救箱吗?
Is there a first-aid box?
没事 我没事
It's fine. I'll be alright.
他们也想害你 他们都想把我们害死
They tried to get you. They're going to knock us all off, I know it.
2WA也出了这样的事
The same thing happened at 2WA.
我确定这只是个意外
I'm sure it's nothing more than a silly accident.
告诉她 费雪小姐
Tell her, Miss Fisher.
我也想这么说 可是...
I'd like to agree, but...
电线是被故意磨碎损的
The wires have been deliberately frayed.
不是的 先生 探长罗宾森自己阻止了电刑
No, sir. Inspector Robinson prevented the electrocution himself.
好的
Yes.
好的 先生
Yes, sir.
我会传达指令
I'll pass on the message.
谢谢你 先生 马上就去
Thank you, sir. Right away.
看起来很自在啊 休斯
Looking right at home there, Hugh.
你急忙执行探长之命时
In your haste to follow the Inspector's orders,
把路易莎・金乐顿的笔记本落下了
you left Louisa Singleton's notebook behind.
谢谢你 小姐 怎么会发生这样的事?
Thank you, Miss. How did that happen?
我们想着你需要些帮手检查路易莎的东西
We thought you might need some help going through Louisa's things.
探长的秘密甜点!
The Inspector's secret stash!
小姐...
Miss...
干得好 休斯
Well done, Hugh.
真好吃
Mm, delicious.
一盒火柴 谢谢
A packet of matches, thanks.
还有 这是给你的
And, ah, this came for you.
特别快送
Special delivery.
谢谢 我一直盼着呢
Thanks. I've been expecting that.
卖报纸!
Paper!
看看这个 休斯
Look at this.
为什么路易莎要买州级火车票?
Why would Louisa buy an interstate train ticket?
一夜旅途去悉尼 下周启程 不予退票
An overnight sleeper to Sydney booked for next week. No return.
克莱瑞斯・鲍尔说海斯尔不喜欢路易莎的想法
Clarence Ball said Hazel didn't like any of Louisa's ideas,
可这是他们今早演出的庞静赫尔家
but this is the Polkinghorns episode they played this morning.
也许是她为海斯尔抄写的
Maybe she was just transcribing for Hazel.
看这里写道 作者 路易莎・金乐顿
Look, it says, 'Written by Miss Louisa Singleton.'
如果所有故事都是路易莎所创作
If all of those stories were Louisa's ideas
海斯尔却赢得名声 我不责备她想离开
and Hazel was taking all the glory, I don't blame her for trying to leave
那晚广播奖 晚上七点才开始的
That radio awards night, it didn't begin until 7:00pm
可是克里斯维奇夫妇五点半就走了
but the Creswicks left the studio at 5:30.
有充分时间可以绕路
That's plenty of time for a detour.
我们要和海斯尔谈谈 下午茶吧
We need a quiet word with Hazel, a casual tete-a-tete.
把车开来 多蒂
Bring the car around, Dot.
两位的茶
Tea For Two.
女人干家务劳累一天
What better, after a woman's long day of household toils
男人在外拼搏奋斗
and a man's daily battles with the world
还有什么比这时来两杯泰利家茶更好的呢?
than a steaming brew for two of Tilley's tea?
致意温暖的家
To celebrate hearth and home...
不论谁人来访
..no matter who comes calling,
或是在夜晚为爱人
or prepare for an evening of loving companionship
在床上送上一杯
with the little ones tucked safely in bed.
泰利家茶 3JH广播赞助商
Tilley's tea, proud sponsor of 3JH Radio,
由轻松与活力打造 为您奉献
is made for relaxation and rejuvenation, just for you.
泰利的茶是泡茶的首选
Tilley's tea is tip-top tea from the very best tips to your teapot.
如果我能借用那个打印机 我能把笔记打给你
If I could borrow that typewriter, I could type these notes for you.
谢谢 多蒂
Thanks, Dottie.
要是我这个做好了 我就离晋升更进一步了
You know, if I do well on this case, I'm one step closer to a promotion,
我们就有钱结婚了
which means we can afford to get married.
当你是休斯・柯林斯太太的时候
Then wise-cracking bird impersonators
才貌双全的你用武之地可要小很多了
won't be so free and easy when you're Mrs Hugh Collins.
我们该怎么跟你妈妈讲 休斯?
How are we going to tell your mother, Hugh?
我不在乎 我们在天主教教堂结婚 我转教
I don't care. We'll get married in a Catholic church. I'll convert.
可那会让你妈妈伤心的
But that would break your mother's heart.
我相信告诉费雪小姐后 她会有办法的
I'm sure if we tell Miss Phryne, she'll help us find a solution.
我们不能自己解决吗?
Can't we work it out ourselves?
你要不为她工作了 我们都要靠自己解决的
That's what we'll have to do when you don't work for her anymore.
什么?
Pardon?
一旦我们定了日子 你就会辞职
Once we set a date and you give notice,
费雪小姐要一人单干了
Miss Fisher's going to have to do without you.
没有我了?
Without me?
放弃我的工作?
Give up my job?
是啊
Right.
多蒂!
Dot!
克里斯维奇先生
Mr Creswick.
我在等你的太太
I was expecting your wife.
海斯尔致上歉意 她受不了汽车劳顿
Hazel sends her apologies, but she wasn't up to the car trip.
你说威廉姆斯小姐能帮忙打字
You thought Miss Williams could help out with our typing.
当然 我很乐意帮忙
Of course. I'd be happy to help.
谢谢你 多蒂
Thank you, Dot.
既然你在这 我想问路易莎的事
While you're here, I would like a quiet word about Louisa.
当然
Of course.
看来她几乎每晚都在为广播剧创作
It seems she dedicated most of her evenings to writing for radio,
可任何作品都未播出?
but nothing of hers has been to air?
路易莎很有抱负 可她没有创作天赋
Louisa was very ambitious, but she had no training as a writer.
她更适合做打字员 海斯尔只用手写
She was needed far more as a typist. Hazel only writes in longhand.
那你怎么解释 今早这一集
Then how do you explain this - this morning's episode,
和路易莎笔记本上的一字不差?
word for word, in Louisa's personal notebook?
真的?
Really?
也许她从海斯尔的手稿中抄出来的
Well, perhaps she copied it from one of Hazel's scripts for some reason,
想学习或者...
to learn from or...
剽窃?
Plagiarism?
我希望事不至此
I hope that's not what it was.
有可能因为这个海斯尔跟她吵架吗?
Could that be why Hazel argued with her?
任何争吵不过一时不快而已
Any arguments they had couldn't have been more than a tiff.
我们工作区域小 很多不合很常见
We work in very close quarters, and disagreements are bound to happen.
路易莎有说过自己有旅行计划吗?
Did Louisa mention that she had any travel plans?
我不知道
Not that I know of.
可是海斯尔很信赖她
But Hazel was very reliant on her,
要是她想搬走 会让她很伤心的
and if she were about to move on, that would have left her in the lurch
是的 如果我们知道 我们都会很伤心
Yes. It would have left us all in the lurch, if we'd known about it.
昨晚你和海斯尔几点到达颁奖典礼?
What time did you and Hazel arrive at the award ceremony last night?
我不确定
I can't be sure.
我们有点迟了
We were a little late.
海斯尔的头疼病犯了
Hazel was nursing one of her headaches,
我要比她先走一步
and I had to go on ahead of her.
所以她呆在家里了?
So she stayed at home?
只待了半个小时
Only for half an hour.
然后她坐上出租车赶上了我
Then she grabbed a cab and joined me.
那真是美好的一晚
It was a wonderful evening.
最开始确实不错 但可惜路易莎遭遇了不幸
To start with, anyway, but it ended sadly for Louisa.
那个 我必须要回电台去了
Look, I have to get back to the station
看看海斯尔是不是完全掌控了
and check Hazel's on top of things.
今天早上我们已经丢了条赞助商的广告播出
We've already missed one sponsor's message this morning.
我对参演很感兴趣 而且我有一些演出经验
I'd be happy to step in. I do have performance experience.
真的吗?
Really?
不管怎么说 我也需要在电台呆着
I need to be around the station in any case.
我不希望海斯尔觉得自己被取代了
I wouldn't want Hazel to feel displaced,
但是 事到如今
but at the moment,
您的提议让我感激万分 费雪小姐
I would be very grateful, Miss Fisher.
来自我们最受欢迎的赞助商的广告
Now a word from our favourite sponsor.
女士们 是否只有奋力搓洗
Ladies, do you scrub your knuckles raw
才能让丈夫的衬衫亮白如新?
to get your husband's shirts white and bright?
孩子的衣服呢?
What about the kiddies?
是不是看上去已经像是褪色的次品一样?
Are their clothes looking faded and second-rate?
那你们真应该试一试华丽炫耀的新型洗衣粉
Well, then, you really should try new Flamboyance washing powder.
# 女士们 仔细听我说 #
# Ladies, listen to the news #
# 再也不必为周一清晨忧虑 #
# No more Monday-morning blues #
# 只要来一小勺华丽炫耀 #
# Just one scoop of Flamboyance #
# 你就可以尽情享受洗衣的快乐 #
# And through your washing day you'll dance #
# 华丽炫耀 华丽炫耀 #
# Flamboyance, Flamboyance #
# 只要来点华丽炫耀 #
# Just a little Flamboyance. #
见鬼!
Damn!
稍作休息 接下来是
A brief tune, then it's news on
整点阿奇伯・琼斯新闻播报
the hour with Archibald Jones.
弦跳出来了
Popped a string.
唱的真不错 费雪小姐
But bravo, Miss Fisher.
我们合作无间真该多亲近些
We make a wonderful team. We should get cosy.
我觉得够亲近的了 谢谢您
I'm quite cosy enough, thank you.
哦 您好
Oh, hello.
需要什么帮助?
Can I help you?
- 晚报 - 哦
- Evening edition. - Oh.
路易莎的变故真太糟了 她是个好姑娘
Bloody awful, what happened to Louisa. She was a real gem.
告诉克莱瑞斯 报纸在这儿
Tell Clarence his paper's here.
他需要它播报赛马新闻
He needs it for his racing show.
你好 多蒂
Hello, Dot.
真不错 小姐
Well done, Miss.
- 您听上去就像专业人士 - 谢谢
- You sounded just like the real thing. - Thank you.
送报员似乎特意要让克莱瑞斯
Our delivery man seemed quite particular
看到他的报纸 是吧?
that Clarence get his newspaper, didn't he?
一个赌注提示
A betting tip.
第六场 荣耀女孩
Race six, Glory Girl.
我以为那条鱼已经死了
I thought that fish was dead.
新买的 一个礼物
It's a new one, a present.
我知道奥斯沃德的死
I know how upset Mrs Creswick
让克里斯维奇女士很难过 所以...
was about poor Oswald, so...
你心肠真好
That's very kind of you.
这没什么的
It wasn't any trouble.
你真是一个好女孩 多蒂
You really are a treasure, Dot.
要是没有你我都不知道该怎么办
I don't know what I'd do without you.
您对我也很重要 小姐
Nor I without you, Miss.
我刚刚听到了广播的结尾
I just heard the end of that broadcast.
你以为自己在做什么 费雪小姐?
What do you think you're doing, Miss Fisher?
海斯尔! 海斯尔 你能否让我解释一下
Hazel! Hazel, if you'll just let me explain.
是我要求费雪小姐来帮忙的
I asked Miss Fisher to step in for us.
这样的话 那我要谢谢您了
In that case, I suppose I should thank you.
不用谢
Not at all.
亲爱的 你随时可以决定是否继续参加
You can be so determined to carry on sometimes, my love.
您需要我帮你剥豆子呢 巴特勒先生?
Are you sure you don't want me to shell the peas, Mr Butler?
不用 我喜欢剥豆子 让我很有满足感
No, no, I enjoy podding peas. It's very satisfying.
比起晚餐来 费雪小姐更依赖于你
And Miss Fisher relies on you for a lot more than her evening meal.
在这儿 我们都做些力所能及的工作
We all help where we can under this roof,
但你可是她无时无刻都需要的得力助手啊
but you are her right-hand woman at all hours of the day and night.
是的 我努力成为她的得力助手
Yes, I try to be her Girl Friday.
要是我住在其它地方 就不太可能了 是吧?
But that wouldn't be possible if I lived anywhere else, would it?
我可不要想这个 多乐茜
Not something I even want to consider, Dorothy.
我们需要一台收音机 我们得听赛马的广播
We need the radio. We've got a date with a horserace.
你们可不能想用无线电了 就随意的闯进来要
Well, you can't just take over the wireless whenever you please.
工作要求 多蒂你看
It's a job, Dottie. Look.
费雪小姐要我们关注这匹马...
Miss Fisher asked us to keep an eye on this horse...
荣耀女孩
Glory Girl.
我们告诉她这老马不行 整个赛季倒数第一
We told her she's a joke. That nag ran last all season.
好吧 那么 就听一场
Alright, then, one race,
但是我要警告你们
but I warn you,
费雪小姐有在...警察局的朋友
Miss Fisher has company...constabulary company.
这家伙真的就在那儿 多蒂他就在赛道上
This guy is actually there, Dottie. He's at the track.
我赌他是在什么树上坐着
Up some bloody tree, I bet,
这样报业同行就不能打击报复了
so the newspapers don't lynch him for stealing their thunder.
罗兰德第六场的赛马已经就位
Lining up for race six in the Rowlands.
外圈第二道是我给你的得冠提示...
Second on the outside is my tip for a win...
四号 巴德兹
No.4, Bedazzler.
我还以为荣耀女孩是他的最爱
I thought Glory Girl was supposed to be his favourite.
外道最后一匹是十四号
Last on the outside is No.14,
荣耀女孩 赛道是湿路面
Glory Girl. It's a wet track here.
都没怎么提到这匹马
She hardly rated a mention.
我觉得自己是在福勒明顿的赛马
I feel like I'm at the bookie's circle
赌博大厅里一样 小点声
at Flemington. Turn it down.
我们没下注真是太幸运了
You're lucky we haven't got a bet on.
... 生于 1926年7月7日
..foaled on 7th July 1926,
她的身体状态还是非常不错
and she is still going strong.
- 赶紧开始啊! - 嘘!
- Just get on with it! - Ssh!
1926年7月7日
7th July 1926.
是谁告诉海斯尔・克里斯维奇
Who told Hazel Creswick
我应该在歌唱圈发展的?
I should diversify into singing?
我不知道 但这确实是一个不错的建议
I'm not sure, but it certainly is a wonderful suggestion.
我拙劣的卧底表现能为
I'm glad my feeble undercover attempt
您提供些消遣 我很高兴
provides you with amusement.
我会在所有阴暗的角落里寻找乐趣 阿奇
I look for joy in all the dark places Archie.
有人付给克莱瑞斯・鲍尔 一大笔钱
So, someone is paying Clarence Ball large amounts of cash,
道奇似乎是他们的中间人
and Dodger looks like the go-between.
他在电台可算是如鱼得水了
He seemed quite at home letting himself into the station,
奇怪的是他在所有的这些
but odd that he only offered up one
比赛中只提供了一条提示
tip in all those races.
可能 "荣耀女孩"是
Perhaps 'Glory Girl'
下一场阴谋破坏的指令
is an instruction for the next act of sabotage.
"荣耀女孩"可能是指海斯尔・克里斯维奇
'Glory Girl' could be Hazel Creswick.
不可能!
No!
她赢了
She won.
那匹该死的老马竟然赢了四个身长
That bloody useless nag won by four lengths.
你好啊 波特!
Hello, Bert!
你们好 费雪小姐 警官
Miss Fisher. Inspector.
阿尔伯特
Albert.
荣耀女孩 赢了比赛 这是一条真实的提示
Glory Girl won that race. Definitely a genuine tip.
但是克莱瑞斯这家伙说的得冠热门却没有赢
Not that that Clarence bloke mentioned it on the radio.
一点都不挨边!
Not even close!
对他的神秘的马驹名誉厅节目更感兴趣了
More interested in all the fan his Hall Of Fame mystery horse.
或许真是条准消息
Maybe it was a real tip.
比起蓄意谋杀
And the money has more to do
也许那笔钱和赛马有更多的联系
with the racetrack than sabotage.
路易莎可能在此犯了错
Louisa may have stumbled on it
所以付出了生命的代价
and paid the price.
我会安排休斯把他们引进来
I'll have Hugh haul both of them in.
那么 道奇 你的真实姓名是约翰・洛克海特
So, Dodger, your real name is John Lockhart.
你和那个臭名昭著的驯马师 恶棍头
Any relation to Neddy Lockhart,
尼德・洛克海特是什么关系?
notorious racehorse trainer and standover man?
他是我的叔叔 怎么了?
He's my uncle. So what?
荣耀女孩 你在报纸上圈了这匹马的名字
Glory Girl, a horse you circled in the newspaper,
今天在第六场比赛里以二十比一的赔率赢了
came in for a win at 20-1 in race six today.
也许你们应该和你叔叔尼德谈一谈
Perhaps we should talk to your Uncle Ned about that.
他和此事无关
He's got nothing to do with it.
我只不过是耳听八方而已
I just keep my ear to the ground.
要是你不希望我们去找拜访一下他的话
If you don't want us to pay him a visit,
就把所有关于克莱瑞斯・鲍尔
tell us everything you know about Clarence Ball
和他的勾当的事情都告诉我们
and his involvement.
我透露些消息给克拉瑞 他把他们广播出来
I pass tips on to Clarry, he puts them on the air.
他有一些特别的代号
He's got some special code.
赌马的人花钱就为了知道这些
Punters pay to get hold of it.
就这些!
That's it!
鲍尔先生 我们对您的
Mr Ball, we're very interested
每日名人堂片段很感兴趣
in your daily Hall Of Fame segment.
请 叫我克拉瑞就可以了
Please, call me Clarry.
不了 谢谢您
No, thank you.
那么您今日的神秘赛马 线索是什么 警员?
Now, your mystery horse today, what was the clue, Constable?
"生于1926年7月7日"
'Foaled 7th July 1926.'
字母表第七个字母 G
Seventh letter of the alphabet, G,
然后是七月 另外一个G 1926年
then the seventh month, another G - 1926.
第六场 荣耀女孩
Race six, Glory Girl.
非常聪明
Very clever.
- 所以说你经营了赛马赌场吗? - 没有
- You're running a book? - No.
道奇把我的代码卖给那些在报摊的赌马的人
Dodger sells my code to the punters from the newsstand,
比赛前我把提示广播出去
I then broadcast the tip before the race.
要是赌马的人想要压钱
If punters want to put money on,
那就是他们自己的事儿了
that's their business,
道奇每天晚上给我钱 是他自己的事儿
and if Dodger pays me cash every night, that's his business.
- 你昨天晚上和道奇见面了吗? - 没有
- You met up with Dodger last night? - No.
昨夜的老时间他没在 他今天给我付的钱
He wasn't there at the usual time. He paid me today.
你们通常什么时候见面?
What time do you usually meet?
节目结束之后 大概七点
After the show, around seven.
昨天晚上我闪烁灯光作为信号让他过来
Last night I flashed the lights to signal him to come up,
但是他没来 所以我就没有等他 然后回家了
but he didn't make it, so I gave up on him and went home.
一个目击者说你卖给金乐顿一个肉桂面包
A witness told us you sold a cinnamon bun to Miss Singleton.
那是什么时间?
What time was that?
大概是六点十五
About quarter past six.
- 然后你做什么了? - 没什么
- What did you do after? - Not much.
整理了一下 锁好报摊 走回家了
Tidied up, locked the stall, walked home.
那你每夜和克莱瑞斯・鲍尔的见面怎么了?
What about your nightly meetings with Clarence Ball?
我投了点收入进去 我下了赌注
I'd spent the takings. I put some bets on.
我没有钱给他 所以我没去找他
I didn't have it to give to him, so I put him off.
你那夜后来有没有去广播站周围的地方?
Did you go anywhere near the radio station later that night?
没有
No.
我把他交给你了 警员
I'll leave him to you, Constable.
阿奇伯・琼斯晚上要带我去城里逛一逛
Archibald Jones is taking me out on the town for the evening.
- 你检查过她的伤口了? - 还没
- Have you seen her injuries? - No.
我一直忙于广播寻羊启示
I've been too busy announcing missing sheep
以及苹果价格
and the price of apples.
但是你做的很好啊 阿奇
But you do it so well, Archie.
法医的报告认为勒杀是死因
The Coroner's report suggests strangulation as the cause of death.
你有没有看到胃容物的报告?
Have you seen these notes on the stomach contents?
"报纸 死者的胃里还发现了一些碎纸片"
'Newspaper. Shreds found in the victim's mouth as well.'
第五页 准确的来讲
Page 5, to be precise.
我们的报纸小贩看上去真是越来越可疑了
Our newspaper seller is looking more and more interesting.
或者是路易莎有些奇怪的饮食习惯
Or Louisa had strange dietary habits.
克莱瑞斯说她经常工作到很晚 会买点东西吃
Clarence said she often worked late and bought something to eat.
除了这个不普通的叉子 你看
Except this is no ordinary fork. Look
可能是在柜子里被夹住了
Could have been caught in a drawer.
这太平了
It's too even.
这个叉子被特意修改过
This fork has been especially modified.
干什么用的?
For what?
我们该回播音室查查
We'll have to return to the studio to find out.
下次要非法闯入的时候记得提醒我带上你
Remind me to bring you on my next break-in.
你真的很有用
You're really quite useful.
多谢
Thank you.
抱歉 我刚只是想扶稳你
Sorry. I was just trying to steady you.
探长 想什么时候扶稳我都行
Steady me anytime, Inspector.
这看起来有希望
This looks hopeful.
更多的赛马泄密?
More racing tips?
体育版没有什么线索
Nothing in the sports pages.
停 停 这有一页不见了
Stop, stop. There's a page missing.
准确地说 第五页
Page 5, to be precise.
很显然路易莎故意把这报纸藏起来
Louisa obviously had this well hidden for a reason.
无论是谁看到这张报纸...
Whoever she confronted with it...
就会让路易莎食言
Made her eat her words.
快! 杰克
Quick, Jack!
跟丢了
Lost him.
看 这和我昨天在犯罪现场发现的空烟盒一样
Look, same as the empty pack I found at the crime scene yesterday.
- 看看这盖子 - 道奇
- Look at the lid. - Dodger.
我见他在报刊亭就拿着一样的烟盒
I saw him with the same pack at the newsstand.
他就是我们要找的纵火犯
Looks like he's our arsonist.
查了一个星期那个狡猾角色的线索
A week of tips like this from that dodgy character,
想想那钱够我们买多少啤酒
think how many beers that's going to buy us.
别提啤酒了 我们会有钱买下整个鲁迪酒吧
Forget the beer. We'll be rich enough to buy the whole Ruddy pub.
你觉得这是怎么回事? 顾客要在这里等
How do you like that? Customers could be waiting.
你们俩在这干什么?
What are you two doing here?
买报纸 这不违法吧
Buying a paper. No law against that.
- 洛克哈特在哪? - 谁?
- Where's Lockhart? - Who?
约翰・洛克哈特 人们叫他道奇
John Lockhart. People call him Dodger.
没听过
Never heard of him.
喔 他在这!
Oi, he's in here!
纵火现场到处都是黑指纹
There were black fingerprints all over the site of the fire
门上 箱子上 新闻纸上
the door, the bin. It's newsprint.
确认是约翰 '道奇' 洛克哈特的
Confirmed as John 'Dodger' Lockhart.
看起来你找到了破坏者
Looks like you found your saboteur.
阿奇 你终于暴露了
You can finally blow your cover, Archie.
但是谁谋杀了道奇?
But who murdered Dodger?
为什么?
And why?
如果有另一个凶手逍遥法外
If there's another killer at large,
那可能不是道奇杀了路易莎
perhaps Dodger didn't kill Louisa.
我怀疑他那晚在播音室
I suspect he was there that night at the radio station.
我同意 你说道奇知道 路易莎正要回播音室
I agree. You said Dodger knew Louisa was heading back to the radio station
如果在遇到克莱瑞斯之前
If he waited to check the coast was clear
他是在等待作案时机
before his meeting with Clarence,
他很可能目击了凶手而不是作案
he could have witnessed a murder rather than committed one.
而现在他付出了代价
And now he's paid the price.
还有这...
And this...
是属于海斯尔・克里斯维奇的
belongs to Hazel Creswick.
我昨天就认出来了
I recognise it from yesterday.
她可能没有看起来的那么无助
She may not be as helpless as she seems.
我仍然怀疑她可以独立完成任意一个谋杀案
I still doubt she's capable of either murder all on her own.
说不定两个案子都是她密谋策划的
Perhaps both the Creswicks conspired.
几乎可以结案了
Almost time for my finale.
我们等会在播音室见
I'll meet you at the radio station.
在海湾正对面可以钓到很多鱼
There's plenty of good fishing available right across the bay.
现在播报维多利亚的天气情况
Now for Victoria's weather.
一个低压气旋将于
A low system will deepen over
今早在海湾水域加强 然后...
the Bight waters this morning, then...
呃 向我国北部移动并有所减弱
ah, move north of the state and weaken.
现在请听一段贝多芬的...
Now for some modern music from...
现代音乐
Beethoven.
阿奇 你在干什么? 你还没播报完天气
Archie, what are you doing? You didn't finish the weather.
就当这是我的辞呈
Consider this my resignation.
我是不是把水落这了? 我来...
Did I leave my water? I came up...
阿奇
Archie.
你是警察
You're a policeman.
事实上是探长 我不是阿奇而是杰克・罗宾森
Detective Inspector, in fact. It's not Archie, it's Jack Robinson.
他们塞给我一个该死的警察作新闻播报员!
They passed me over as newsreader for a bloody cop!
现在 克里斯维奇夫妇
Now, Mr and Mrs Creswick,
我必须要求你同我去播音室
I must ask you to accompany me to the station
回答关于约翰・洛克哈特死因的一些问题
to answer questions about the death of John Lockhart,
也就是道奇
otherwise known as Dodger.
我早就告诉你那是我的
I already told you it's mine.
我还纳闷是在哪丢的呢
I wondered where I'd lost it.
那你怎么解释它出现报刊亭里呢?
How do you explain it being found inside the newsstand?
我不知道
I have no idea,
但我通常在接电话的时候把一个耳坠取下来
but I usually take one off when I answer the telephone.
你无论问谁
Ask anyone.
问吉米 他会告诉你我昨晚在哪
Ask Jimmy. He'll tell you where I was last night.
柯林斯?
Collins?
柯林斯!
Collins!
把克里斯维奇先生带进来
Bring Mr Creswick through.
他不相信我
He doesn't believe me.
没事 亲爱的
It's alright, my love.
我们昨晚一直在家
We were home all evening.
我们排练第二天的演出 吃饭 上床睡觉
We ran through our lines for the next day, ate dinner, went to bed.
任何人都有可能捡到海斯尔的耳坠
Anyone could have picked up Hazel's earring.
为什么凶手试图暗示你的妻子呢?
Why would the murderer try and implicate your wife?
我怎么知道?
How should I know?
你是一直监视着我们的优秀侦探
You're the fancy detective who's been spying on us.
如果你都不能查清是怎么回事
If you can't work out what's going on,
那我们还有什么希望?
what hope have we got?
抱歉 先生
Excuse me, sir.
可能有你想要听的消息刚传来了
Information has just come through that you might like to hear.
克里斯维奇先生 请您和您妻子在外面等一下
Mr Creswick, if you'd like to wait outside with your wife.
吉米 我不知道今天该怎么完成表演
I don't know how I'm going to get through the show today, Jimmy.
亲爱的 我们会成功的 我们一直都是
We'll manage, my darling. We always do.
费雪小姐 你没有抛弃我们俩个 对吧?
You haven't abandoned us two, have you, Miss Fisher?
你们今天还会演格温妮亚?
You will still play Guinevere today?
无论如何我都不会错过的
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
验尸官打电话来证实
The Coroner telephoned to confirm
最新的受害者是被粗钢丝勒死的
the latest victim was strangled with heavy wire,
可能是钢琴丝
possibly piano wire.
克莱瑞斯昨天在播音室弄断了一根钢琴丝
Clarence broke a piano wire at the station yesterday.
那怎么解释耳坠的事?
How do you explain the earring?
试图陷害海斯尔?
An attempt to frame Hazel?
她和克莱瑞斯毫无感情
There was no love lost between her and Clarence.
当我们找到丢了的第五页或许会更了解这件事
Perhaps we'll know more when we find our missing page 5.
柯林斯 查一下档案
Check with Archives, Collins.
多蒂 你终于来了
Oh, Dot. Good.
我尽快赶来了 要我做些什么?
I came as fast as I could. What did you need me to do?
我要去直播了
I'm due on air.
我需要你帮我把更多的证据送去警察局给休斯
I need you to take more evidence to the police station for Hugh
我还要讲述特苏坎越轨的行为
while I recount my Tuscan escapades.
可怜的奥斯沃德二世
Poor Oswald II.
克里斯维奇会被吓坏的
Mrs Creswick will be devastated.
是的 一条死了的金鱼是不幸的
Yes. One dead goldfish is unfortunate
但两条就是谋杀
but two points to foul play.
费雪小姐想让警察局化验所
Miss Fisher would like the police laboratory
检查一下水质和奥斯沃德
to test the water and Oswald.
为什么?
For what?
她觉得有人在奥斯沃德的水里放了什么东西
She thinks someone might have put something in his water.
宠物店的人让我把鱼缸清理干净 但我忘记了
The man at the pet store told me to clean his bowl out, but I forgot.
啊 多蒂 这不是你的错
Aw, Dottie. It's not your fault.
休斯 不是那样
It's not that, Hugh.
呆在这 我去取个测水质的瓶子
Stay here. I'll get a jar to test the water.
- 我会回来的 - 不是关于鱼的事
- I'll be back. - It's not about the fish.
是我们俩
It's about us.
我不知道这意味着什么
I didn't think what it would mean.
啊?
What?
婚姻 一场婚礼
Marriage, a wedding.
休斯 我想和你在一起 真的
I want to be with you, Hugh, I do,
但我也想为费雪小姐工作
but I want to work for Miss Fisher too.
那不行的 你工作的话
Well, that wouldn't be right, you working,
就不能当休斯・柯林斯太太了
not when you're Mrs Hugh Collins.
我知道
I know.
多蒂 你在做什么?
Dottie, what are you doing?
我不知道我想要什么
I don't know what I want.
这是什么?
What is this?
不!
No!
多蒂 等一下 多蒂!
Dottie, wait. Dottie!
柯林斯 怎么了?
What's going on, Collins?
呃...
Ah...
长官 又发生一起谋杀案
we've had another murder, sir.
我是说 威廉姆斯小姐
I meant, Miss Williams.
我一直在想 什么时候可以和多蒂确定婚期
I always thought, sir, that when Dottie and I set a date,
假设她同意的话 她可以不再为费雪小姐工作
assuming she agreed, she'd stop working for Miss Fisher
和我一起组建家庭
and make a home for us both.
我以为她会很乐意
I thought she'd be happy to.
但现在她好像不愿意放弃工作
But now it seems that she doesn't want to stop working,
而她也不高兴
and she's not happy.
柯林斯 你所经历的
What you're experiencing, Collins,
是追求一个现代女性的矛盾
is the paradox of pursuing a modern woman.
多蒂是一位现代女性?
Dottie's a modern woman?
她和一位现代女性住了一段时间 近朱者赤
She's been living with one for a while. It's bound to rub off.
首先 瓦乐瑞很可爱
At first, Valerio was lovely,
但接着他把我锁在特苏坎城堡底下的地牢里
but then he locked me in a dungeon under his Tuscan castle.
幸运的是 我成功说服了侍卫
Fortunately, I managed to persuade the guard
把我从秘密通道里偷送出来
to smuggle me out through a secret passage.
哦 我的女儿多么勇敢 对吧? 乌苏拉
Oh, my. How brave our daughter is. Don't you agree, Ursula?
我不会说她勇敢 但她很有胆量又足智多谋
I wouldn't say brave. Plucky, maybe. Resourceful.
那不是一个安全的地牢
It wasn't a very secure dungeon,
我不知道该不该告诉你们那侍卫的一切
and I'm not sure that I should tell you everything about the guard.
格温妮亚 有你在我们就放心了
Guinevere, we are truly relieved to have you...
呃 亲爱的 我们非常感激
Well, my dear, we are very grateful
你能安然无恙地回来
to have you home again, safe and sound.
喝杯茶庆祝一下吧
Perhaps a cup of tea to celebrate.
还有...
And...
唱支歌!
a song!
你怎么不告诉我你不舒服?
Why didn't you tell me you were so ill?
不 吉米 我只是太紧张了
I'm not, Jimmy. It's just nerves.
谢谢你 费雪小姐 我会送她回家
Thank you, Miss Fisher. I'll take her home.
医生会在那帮她治疗的
The doctor can see her there.
算了吧 我不需要看医生 我要播报完天气
No, please. I don't need a doctor. I need to finish the broadcast.
不 你需要 走吧
No, you don't. Come on.
你听广播没 多蒂?
Did you hear the broadcast, Dot?
庞静赫尔家今天又草草收尾了
The Polkinghorns came to another abrupt ending today.
我听了 小姐
Yes, Miss.
你这是怎么了?
What on earth is the matter?
休斯向我求婚了
Hugh proposed.
他想宣布这个消息 然后我们定下婚期
He wants to announce it so we can set a date.
是个喜讯啊
That's wonderful news.
不 它不是
No, it's not.
如果我嫁给休斯 我就再也不能为你工作了
If I marry Hugh, I won't be able to work for you anymore.
噢 多蒂
Oh, Dot.
我不能再和你一起查案
I won't go on investigations with you
记笔记 练打字
and take notes and improve my typing
开车去兜风
and go motoring with you in the Hispano.
多蒂 你讨厌坐我的车
Dot. You hate motoring with me.
没错 但是其他的我都喜欢啊
Yes, but I love everything else,
那些也到此为止了
and all that will end
因为... 休斯想着女人
because... that's the way
结婚后在家相夫教子
Hugh sees it,
传统思想中女人的宿命 小姐
and that's the way things are for married women, Miss.
那不代表所有女人都得如此
That doesn't mean that's the way things have to stay.
特件 - 路易莎的最后一餐
Special delivery - Louisa's last meal.
谢谢 杰克
Thank you, Jack.
我开始怀念阿奇・琼斯了
I think I'm going to miss Archie Jones.
你自己起的那名? 和你的金领带挺配的
Did you choose that name yourself? It did suit your gold tie.
你就看第五版吧
Just look at page 5.
出生 丧亲 艾尔伍德走失了只博美犬
Births. Bereavements. A lost Pomeranian in Elwood.
这版对路易莎来说有什么特殊意义?
What made this page so special to Louisa?
柯林斯说威廉姆斯小姐可能会发现点蛛丝马迹
Collins suggested Miss Williams might have more luck.
真的吗? 我马上给她
Really? I'll give it to her immediately.
多蒂最近一直垂头丧气的
Dot has been rather upset lately.
休斯还没告诉你 是吗?
Hugh hasn't spoken to you, has he?
他确实要我给点建议
He did seek my advice, yes.
你怎么和他说的?
And what did you tell him?
那个我觉得 是内部机密
That, I believe, is confidential police information.
就像这个
Like this.
两条金鱼的死因 - 铊 用于制作灭鼠药
Cause of death of two goldfish - thallium. It's found in rat poison.
无色无味融于水
Odourless, colourless and dissolves in water.
海斯尔喝了大量的水 铊也会引起脱发
Hazel drinks a great deal of water. Thallium also causes hair loss.
需要控制在低剂量才能使受害者只脱发
It would have to be a low dose for the victim to lose their hair,
而不致命
otherwise they just die.
所以海斯尔是被下药了
So Hazel is being poisoned,
小心谨慎 一次又一次?
slowly and carefully?
投毒者惯用伎俩
The poisoner's poison.
小姐!
Miss!
小姐 找到了! 我发现线索了
Miss, I found it! I found the clue.
- 这不可能只是巧合 - 从头说 多蒂
- It can't just be a coincidence. - From the beginning, Dot.
公告 悼念 这儿
Public Notices, In Memoriam. Here.
"雷德巴斯, 格温妮亚
"Redpath, Guinevere.
生于1895卒于1925年
1895 - 1925.
在巴斯惨遭杀害 沉痛悼念
Sadly missed. Tragically killed in Perth.
因主播暮光旋律为大众铭记
Fondly remembered for her Twilight Melodies broadcast.
法网恢恢疏而不漏"
Justice will prevail."
格温妮亚是路易莎在庞静赫尔家里用的名字
Guinevere was the name Louisa used in The Polkinghorns.
路易莎在巴斯住了一年
Louisa lived in Perth for a year.
她可能知道点格温妮亚的事
She could have known this Guinevere.
但是为什么她要把报纸藏起来?
But why would she hide this notice?
克里斯维奇小姐请进 谢谢
Mrs Creswick. Come in. Thank you.
海斯尔 你看起来不太好
Hazel, you're not well.
你再替我主播一次行吗 费雪小姐?
Please will you fill in again for me, Miss Fisher?
你能看出来 我撑不住
I'm not up to it, as you can see.
进客厅来
Come into the parlour.
看好她
Make sure she stays here.
我叫休斯搜索下格温妮亚・雷德巴斯的资料
I'll have Hugh hunt up the file on Guinevere Redpath.
我很乐意再帮你一次忙 海斯尔
I'm happy to help you out again, Hazel,
但前提是我必须送你送医院
but only if you let me take you to hospital as soon as I'm done.
我想你不知道自己病得多严重
I'm not sure you realise how ill you are.
不 我很好
No. I'm alright.
我不得不好
I have to be.
下周我就要开始新工作了
I'm moving to start my new job next week.
那张去悉尼的票 不是路易莎的 是你的
That ticket to Sydney, it wasn't Louisa's, it was yours.
新国家广播台
The new National Broadcasting Service,
他们从全国各地召集播音员
they're gathering presenters
选中了我
from all around the country, and they want me.
真光荣 祝贺你
That's quite an honour. Congratulations.
但是我不能突然离开3Jh
But I couldn't leave 3JH in the lurch,
所以我训练路易莎来接手
so I was training Louisa to take over.
她给我订好票
She booked the ticket for me.
海斯尔 你听说过巴斯的
Hazel, have you ever heard of a
格温妮亚・雷德巴斯么?
Guinevere Redpath from Perth?
或者暮光旋律? 这是个电台节目
Or Twilight Melodies? It's a radio show.
没有 你可以去我们的档案室查查
No, but you could look in our archives.
路易莎负责整理归类
Louisa was in charge of cataloguing them.
多蒂 照顾好海斯尔 到时间广播了
Dot, look after Hazel. I'm due on air
一位格温妮亚・雷德巴斯小姐
A Mrs Guinevere Redpath,
暮光旋律6Kb电台的女高音
soprano on Radio 6KB's Twilight Melodies.
被发现死于科特赛罗
Discovered dead in her bed at 27
肯特街27号自家床上 年仅30岁
Kent Street, Cottesloe, aged 30.
- 警局调查结果呢? - 不确定 先生
- Police inquiry? - Inconclusive, sir.
他们五年了也没有找到死者的丈夫协助调查
They were never able to interview her husband of five years,
哈瑞・雷德巴斯先生 一个无线电技术员
a Mr Harry Redpath, a wireless technician.
哈瑞・雷德巴斯杀害他妻子的可能性很大
Harry Redpath could have killed his wife,
搭火车逃往墨尔本 再改名换姓
caught a train to Melbourne, changed his name.
你觉得是他杀了路易莎・金乐顿 先生?
You think he's Louisa Singleton's killer, sir?
也是给海斯尔・克里斯维奇下毒的人
And Hazel Creswick's poisoner.
为什么你不告诉克里斯维奇先生
Why haven't you told Mr Creswick
这个工作的事情?
about the job opportunity?
这么大一个喜讯
It's such exciting news.
威廉姆斯小姐 你有没有爱一人至深
Miss Williams, have you ever loved a man so much
为他牺牲自由也在所不惜?
you'd sacrifice your freedom?
我所知电台的一切都是吉米教的
Jimmy taught me everything I know about radio.
他造就了我 他爱我
He made me and he adores me,
但他从不给我独当一面的机会
but he won't let me do anything on my own.
他不给我一分钱 不允许我驾驶
He won't let me have any money, he won't let me drive
也不准离开他寸步
or go anywhere without him.
我快窒息了
I feel like I'm suffocating.
接下来能播这个么? 特殊要求
Could you play this next? Special request.
我能提个特殊要求作报偿么?
Do I get one in return?
省省吧 克拉瑞 我对你一点兴趣也没有
Save your breath, Clarry. Your charms are lost on me.
骗人
Liar.
现在是特殊播报
And now, a very special treat.
一起回顾过去 - 暮光旋律
A taste of the past - Twilight Melodies.
晚上好 音乐发烧友们
Good evening, music lovers.
欢迎来到暮光旋律
Welcome to Twilight Melodies
这里是哈瑞和格温・雷德巴斯
with Harry and Gwinny Redpath.
吉米!
Jimmy!
我妻子呢 费雪小姐?
Where is my wife, Miss Fisher?
我不知道
I have no idea.
她最好快点来
She'd better be here soon.
可能是毒药害她慢吞吞的
Perhaps the poison slowed her down.
被路易莎发现了 是吗 哈瑞?
Louisa found you out, didn't she, Harry?
在巴斯的那段时间 她记住了你的声音
Remembered your voice from her time in Perth.
接着格温妮亚的悼念公告又唤醒了她的记忆
And then Guinevere's memorial notice jogged her memory.
她用了格温妮亚的名字 观察你的反应
She put Guinevere's name into the script to see how you'd react
然后播放旧时录音以确认
and ordered that old recording just to make sure.
海斯尔来之前你哪也不准去
You're not going anywhere until Hazel gets here.
- 我现在就要见她 - 为什么
- I want her now. - Why,
你就能像杀了第一任妻子一样杀了她?
so you can kill her like you killed your first wife?
- 安静 - 你不会对我开枪
- Be quiet. - You're not going to shoot me.
那有意义吗?
What would be the point in that?
我去报警
I'm calling the police.
你把犯头疼的妻子独自留在家中
You left your wife at home with her headache
自己去了颁奖晚会
before you went to the awards night.
先生 多蒂打电话来 费雪小姐有麻烦了
Sir, Dot's on the telephone. Miss Fisher's in trouble.
你回到工作室再次投毒
You came back here to the studio to poison her again
但是被路易莎抓了个现形
but Louisa caught you in the act.
是你
It's you.
你把她的尸体运走
You dragged her body outside.
克莱瑞斯毫无所觉
Clarence couldn't hear any of it.
接着你若无其事地去参加颁奖晚会
Then you continued on to the awards night as if nothing had happened,
可怜的老道奇目睹了一切
and poor old Dodger saw it all.
你意识到他看到了案发过程
You realised he witnessed the murder,
所以你把他也杀了
so you killed him too.
海斯尔走进这扇门前 你不准动
You're not moving until Hazel walks through that door.
她违抗了我 如果我不能拥有她
She defied me, and if I can't have her,
没有人能够拥有
no-one will.
我要杀了她
I will kill her.
也包括你 费雪小姐
And I'll kill you too, Miss Fisher.
你做了什么?
What have you done?
你的下场会和路易莎一样
You'll get the same as Louisa.
费雪小姐?
Miss Fisher?
观赏愉快 杰克
Hope you enjoyed the show, Jack.
- 警官  - 拉他起来
- Constable, - get him up.
哈瑞・雷德巴斯 现以蓄意杀害
Harry Redpath, you're under arrest
格温妮亚・雷德巴斯之罪逮捕你
for the murders of Guinevere Redpath,
还有路易莎・金乐顿和约翰・洛克海特
Louisa Singleton and John Lockhart.
加上谋杀海斯尔・克里斯维奇未遂
And the attempted murder of Hazel Creswick.
你不用着急赶来
You took your time.
想要恢复原样了吗?
Might want to put this back on?
可我们怎么解决那些问题?
But how will we solve everything?
这是个悖论 多蒂- 让时间去解决一切
It's a paradox, Dottie - a problem that takes time to solve,
对我来说是时候了解现代女性了
time for me to understand the modern woman.
和我恋爱长跑 你开心么?
So you're happy for a long engagement, then?
我很开心
I'm happy.
我也是
Me too.
我想要敬杯酒
I would like to propose a toast.
你也是 巴特勒先生 请满上
You too, Mr Butler. I insist.
敬两位我最亲爱的人
To two of the dearest people I know.
敬多蒂 我强大的靠山 左膀右臂
To Dot, my Rock of Gibraltar, my strong right hand.
当然 还有休斯
And, of course, to Hugh,
即使沉静也有让人无法抵抗的警官魅力
that purveyor of quiet yet irresistible constabulary charm.
敬多蒂和休斯
To Dot and Hugh.
多蒂和休斯
Dot and Hugh.
B先生
Mr B.
阿奇 看样子回归你的旧生活了
So, Archie, looks like it's back to your old life
别为我停下
Don't stop because of me.
# 我们都是形单影只的 #
We're all alone, no chaperone
# 成为我们中的一员 #
Can get our number
# 世界陷入了沉睡 #
The world's in slumber
# 让我们随心所欲 #
Let's misbehave
# 你身上有股狂热 孩子 #
There's something wild about you, child
# 如此动人心弦 #
That's so contagious
# 让我们离经叛道 #
Let's be outrageous
# 让我们随心所欲 #
Let's misbehave
# 你懂我是真心的 #
You know my heart is true
#你说过关心我#
And you say you for me care
#一定有人会说#
Somebody's sure to tell
# 但我们到底关心什么? #
But what the heck do we care?
# 他们说即使熊和骆驼也有爱情 #
They say that bears have love affairs and even camels
# 我们也只是哺乳动物 #
We're merely mammals
# 让我们随心所欲 #
Let's misbehave
# 我们也只是哺乳动物 #
We're merely mammals
# 让我们随心所欲 #
Let's misbehave.